# MEREDITH STRICKLAND

Full Stack Web Developer | www.mere-strickland.com | mere.strickland@gmail.com

### o LINKS o

Github
LinkedIn
Technical Project Demos
Portfolio Website

# PROFILE

With experience in JavaScript, React, and Ruby on Rails, I have a background in Architecture and an eye for design. I am passionate about social justice, and believe that inclusivity in the development of tools and technologies that we all use can improve the world we live in.

## o SKILLS o

JavaScript React

Ruby on Rails

Node.js

Express

**AWS Amplify** 

Heroku

Git

HTML

CSS

Adobe Illustrator
Adobe Photoshop
AutoCAD

# TECHNICAL PROJECTS

# Tr(aid) - GitHub Demo

A platform for members of a community to ask for or offer help during Covid-19.

- · Winner of the Essteem Equalithon, April 2020
- Built front-end UI components using React and Bootstrap
- · Set up back-end models and controllers using Ruby on Rails
- · Reviewed and approved pull requests on GitHub

#### Rita – Slideshow Demo

Prototype for an app that helps caregivers communicate with each other and keep track of appointments, medications, and daily to-dos

- Winner of the "People's Choice Award" at LYLAS Labs: Women at Work Hackathon
- · Collaborated with team to design and build a prototype
- Managed the team from conception to presentation

# Trip List - GitHub Demo

A website where users can add recommendations of things to do in a certain location, search for others recommendations, and add/manage trips to take and ideas for what to do there.

- · Designed and built front-end using React, Redux, HTML, CSS, and Semantic UI React
- · Utilized JSON web tokens and local storage to store encrypted user information
- · Designed and built back-end using Ruby on Rails

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Broadnet, Technical Support

March 2020 - present, remote

- Train clients on the live event interface
- Troubleshoot any issues the client may have with the Broadnet interface
- Follow up with clients to resolve problems in a timely manner
- Provide support in the form of procedural documentation.

# Trustforte Corporation, Technical Writer

November 2017 - present, New York, NY

- Analyze documentation to write 15 educational and professional experience evaluations per week of clients' qualifications for IT positions
- Edit and write technical documents in support of candidates applying for U.S. H-1B visas

# Andrew Franz Architect, Designer and Office Manager

January 2016 - March 2017 and Summer 2018, New York, NY

- Served as a project manager, scheduling approvals and deadlines between consultants, contractors, and fabricators
- · Designed graphics for the company website
- Collaborated with principals researching the most appropriate design schemes for 5 different projects simultaneously

### **EDUCATION**

#### Flatiron School, Full Stack Web Development

December 2018 - June 2019, Brooklyn, NY

# Bennington College, Architecture

Class of 2011, Bennington, VT